[
    {
        "description": "a wise mage.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I can help.", 
        "keyword_1": "HELP", 
        "keyword_2": "RIDDLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The riddle!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "If the eight philosophies of avatarhood combine into, and are made from Truth, Love & Courage...", 
        "name": "Joshua", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "More?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "What one thing creates, and is created by all Truths, all Love & all Courage?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a fair maiden.", 
        "health": "Fine thanks.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I can help thee.", 
        "keyword_1": "HELP", 
        "keyword_2": "ONE THING", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Seek ye to know how the eight Virtues form into the Three Principles.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Seek ye to know what one thing the Three Principles of Virtue combine into!", 
        "name": "Juliet", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Know ye this?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Seek it!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Now the one!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a dancing jester.", 
        "health": "Perfectly hoppy!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "To entertain.", 
        "keyword_1": "JESTER", 
        "keyword_2": "GOOD BARD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A jester needs a good bard!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Our bard is very good.", 
        "name": "Jester Twin", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou like the music?", 
        "question_no_answer": "A shame, we do!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then you should go to Britain for there lives the best!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a burly guard.", 
        "health": "Great!", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I guard the castle and my liege!", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "LIEGE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A guard must be a valiant warrior!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I serve Lord British!", 
        "name": "A Guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou the most valiant warrior?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Still flee not from battle!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then thou should be a guard!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a person with a white hat.", 
        "health": "Well.. All but my finger, which I cut!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am the chef.", 
        "keyword_1": "CHEF", 
        "keyword_2": "TO COOK", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Food, glorious food, to cook is my life!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Cooking is a practiced art.", 
        "name": "Le Chef", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Do you eat?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then thou must be a spiritualist!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then thou should try my soup!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a reaper.", 
        "health": "Not so good, no one to eat in here!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I kill adventurers!", 
        "keyword_1": "KILL", 
        "keyword_2": "THING", 
        "keyword_response_1": "There is a thing which can kill many!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Knowledge of it is found at Buccaneer's Den!", 
        "name": "A Reaper", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Will you seek this thing?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then thou must be stupid.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "It brings great power!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 32
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a ragged soul.", 
        "health": "Very poor.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I have none.", 
        "keyword_1": "PRISONER", 
        "keyword_2": "CRIME", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Here I pay for my crimes!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Crime is an evil thing!", 
        "name": "A Nameless Prisoner", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Are you a Pirate?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I hope that this is true!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "You may never complete thy quests, for evil makes not an Avatar!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise mage.", 
        "health": "I am old, very old....", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am here to help thee.", 
        "keyword_1": "HELP", 
        "keyword_2": "CASTLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Seek help in the castles!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Seek: the Lycaeum, Empath Abbey, Serpent's Castle!", 
        "name": "Zorin", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wilt thou go hither?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Find therein all named Antos and ask of the bell, book, and candle!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a burly guard.", 
        "health": "Couldn't be better!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I guard the castle and all within.", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "CASTLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I guard the castle!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The castle is fair and strong!", 
        "name": "A Guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Do you seek Lord British?", 
        "question_no_answer": "He will aid you if you are in need!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "He is on the upper level in the throne room.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "Water.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I hold a secret.", 
        "keyword_1": "SECRET", 
        "keyword_2": "ALTARS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "To what?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "There are three Altar Rooms which connect the bottom levels of all eight dungeons!", 
        "name": "Water", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "More?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "If the correct Colors of Stones are used in the Altars, a Key of Three Parts can be gained!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a shepherdess, both strong and beautiful.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I watch the water.", 
        "keyword_1": "WATER", 
        "keyword_2": "PEACE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "It brings me peace.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I come from a proud city.", 
        "name": "Shawn", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Art thou proud?", 
        "question_no_answer": "My towne was destroyed for its Pride. The ruins lie on an isle at lat-K'J\" long-L'L\"!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Hmmm.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an injured fighter.", 
        "health": "I have a grievous wound.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I fight for my country.", 
        "keyword_1": "WOUND", 
        "keyword_2": "COUNTRY", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Deep.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Britannia.", 
        "name": "Seesha", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Fight ye for Britannia?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Hmm.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then seek out the smith named Zircon in Minoc for he made the Mystic Arms, only they will save thee in the Abyss!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a bouncing jester.", 
        "health": "Good, thanks.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am the royal jester", 
        "keyword_1": "ROYAL JESTER", 
        "keyword_2": "CLUE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Welcome unto the Castle Britannia!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Speak ye unto the waters of the well and ask of Altars!", 
        "name": "Chuckles", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou an Ankh?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then why art thou here?", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then enter in peace!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a guard.", 
        "health": "Excellent", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "A guard", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "TREASURES", 
        "keyword_response_1": "We guard the castle and its treasures.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "That is not your business.", 
        "name": "A Guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Do you mean to steal?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then please leave at once!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I believe you will find that an unfruitful venture.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a solemn ranger.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I search for the Inner Light.", 
        "keyword_1": "INNER LIGHT", 
        "keyword_2": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Seek Inner Light in the Shrines!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Runes are needed to enter Shrines!", 
        "name": "Sheila", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou know of Mantra?", 
        "question_no_answer": "The Mantra are chants needed to focus thy thoughts while meditating.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a grim shepherd.", 
        "health": "I am fine, but thou must go back!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am here to warn thee!", 
        "keyword_1": "WARN", 
        "keyword_2": "PERILOUS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Ahead lies a perilous place!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Once thou enters thou may not return whence thee came!", 
        "name": "Landri", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wilt thou go on?", 
        "question_no_answer": "That is good.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then thou art doomed!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a stately baron.", 
        "health": "Very well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I rule this province.", 
        "keyword_1": "PROVINCE", 
        "keyword_2": "WORD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "My Lady Beth can tell thee more!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I know but one of three syllables.", 
        "name": "Robert Frasier", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou wish to know it now?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Perhaps another time.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "It is 'ver'! Seek ye now the other parts!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a charming lady.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I rule with my Lord.", 
        "keyword_1": "RULE", 
        "keyword_2": "PROVINCE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "This province.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Our people believe in Truth as a way of life and live it to the fullest!", 
        "name": "Beth Frasier", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou seek Truth?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then thou shalt not find it!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then may thou find it!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a sleepy guard.", 
        "health": "Very sleepy.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Guard the gate, guard the  baron, guard the baroness, watch the towers....", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "HOURS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I have been here for hours!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Yes, many hours!", 
        "name": "A Guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "See why I'm tired?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Bum!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "It's hard work and long hours in the baronial guard!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 14
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise old sage.", 
        "health": "My bones ache but my mind is sharp!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am an old wizard, but have much to show!", 
        "keyword_1": "SHOW", 
        "keyword_2": "TELESCOPE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Here in my telescope!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Search there by the end, thou shalt find a knob.", 
        "name": "Palamar", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou see where?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Look!!!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Set the dial and thou shalt see!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an old druid, who looks strangely familiar.", 
        "health": "Old and frail, I've seen many quests!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I hold great knowledge.", 
        "keyword_1": "KNOWLEDGE", 
        "keyword_2": "BOOK", 
        "keyword_response_1": "What is it you seek?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Seek ye the Book of Truth where other books lie.", 
        "name": "Father Antos", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou on the quest?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "May thou succeed!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a brawny guard.", 
        "health": "Bit tired.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I guard the throne room.", 
        "keyword_1": "THRONE ROOM", 
        "keyword_2": "TRUTH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Throne of Truth!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "There are four townes that follow the Principle of Truth.", 
        "name": "Jon", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Know which?", 
        "question_no_answer": "There are eight possible combinations of the Three Principles, there are eight cities!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall mage wearing strange armour.", 
        "health": "Well!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I advise.", 
        "keyword_1": "ADVISE", 
        "keyword_2": "ARMOUR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Thou would be well advised to visit the Seer often!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I wear Mystic Armour.", 
        "name": "Scatu", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou a partial Avatar?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "When thou art 8 parts Avatar, seek Zircon in Minoc and ask of Mystics!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a short druid.", 
        "health": "Why I am fine, you too I hope.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "Research", 
        "keyword_1": "RESEARCH", 
        "keyword_2": "JUSTICE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I am looking for the Book of Justice!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It must be here somewhere!", 
        "name": "Estro", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou never committed *any* crime!?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then speak to the judge in Yew!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I believe thou art boasting a lie!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a stately wizard.", 
        "health": "Very well, thanks!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "To welcome thee!", 
        "keyword_1": "TO WELCOME", 
        "keyword_2": "4", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Yes, welcome to the Lycaeum, the keep of Truth!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The dungeon Altar Rooms need 4 Stones each!", 
        "name": "Tymus", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Know ye how many cities follow the Principles of Truth?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Travel and learn!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "How many?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a person lost in thought.", 
        "health": "I am in a meditative state.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek to know Truth.", 
        "keyword_1": "TRUTH", 
        "keyword_2": "MEDITATE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The Principle upon which I meditate.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Meditate at each Shrine for 1, 2 and 3 minutes, then shalt thou know the paths of goodness!", 
        "name": "A Truth Seeker.", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "", 
        "question_no_answer": "", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an injured warrior.", 
        "health": "My wounds are grievous!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "None now!", 
        "keyword_1": "WARRIOR", 
        "keyword_2": "WOUNDS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "No more!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I lost in a dungeon Altar Room!", 
        "name": "A Fighter", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou seen one?", 
        "question_no_answer": "They connect the dungeons unto each other!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Notice that each of the three rooms connect to four dungeons each!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall agile man.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am the librarian.", 
        "keyword_1": "LIBRARIAN", 
        "keyword_2": "TRUTH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Herein is the largest store of knowledge in Britannia except the Codex!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Look under 't'", 
        "name": "Lord Terence", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou looking for a particular book?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Feel free to browse.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Which book?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a flighty jester.", 
        "health": "Unhappy.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "To entertain!", 
        "keyword_1": "TO ENTERTAIN", 
        "keyword_2": "UNHAPPY", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Ah, not now.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Because my friend Chuckles won't tell me his secret!", 
        "name": "Zajac", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou know chuckles?", 
        "question_no_answer": "He lives in the castle Britannia ask him of his clue!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Why dost thou not ask him for his clue!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a strong guard.", 
        "health": "Very good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "To watch the treasures.", 
        "keyword_1": "TREASURE", 
        "keyword_2": "GREAT VALUE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The treasures are of great value!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Yes, much gold.", 
        "name": "Catriona", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou intend to steal?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Good, you had me worried!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I shan't stop thee", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a noble wizard.", 
        "health": "Good enough.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I teach magical spells.", 
        "keyword_1": "SPELLS", 
        "keyword_2": "RESURRECT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I have a specialty!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Yes, Resurrection it takes: Ash, Ginseng, Garlic, Silk, Bloodmoss, and Mandrake!", 
        "name": "Nigel, at thy service.", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou know what it is?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Sorry.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "What do I call the spell?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a pitiful beggar.", 
        "health": "I am cold and sick!\u0001oh... please...", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I sit and beg\u0001oh... please...", 
        "keyword_1": "BEG ", 
        "keyword_2": "SICK", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Yes, please give me money!\u0001oh... please...", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I have the Black Plague!", 
        "name": "Shylock the Meek", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wilt thou help me?\u0001Oh... please...", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh... please...", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Oh... please...", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a stately baron.", 
        "health": "Very well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I rule this province.", 
        "keyword_1": "PROVINCE", 
        "keyword_2": "WORD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "My Lady Marcy can tell thee more!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I know but one of three syllables.", 
        "name": "Lord Robert", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou wish to know it now?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Perhaps another time.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "It is 'amo' seek ye now the other parts!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a charming lady.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I rule with my Lord.", 
        "keyword_1": "RULE", 
        "keyword_2": "PROVINCE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "This province.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Our people believe in Love as a way of life and live it to the fullest!", 
        "name": "Lady Marcy", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou seek Love?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then thou shalt not find it!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then may thou find it!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a lovely lady.", 
        "health": "Overworked!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a lady in waiting.", 
        "keyword_1": "LADY", 
        "keyword_2": "HORN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I serve Marcy.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "There is a paladin by the name of Malchor. He can lead thee to the Silver Horn!", 
        "name": "Suzanna", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Art thou allowed to be in here?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou should leave!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I doubt it! Thou should leave!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 40
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an Ankh.", 
        "health": "I exist.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I resonate thoughts.", 
        "keyword_1": "RESONATE", 
        "keyword_2": "LOVE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "What are thy thoughts?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Seek ye the Candle of Love for only with it and two other parts might thou enter the Abyss!", 
        "name": "Life.", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Dost thou have it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ask the bard beyond the secret passage!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a guard.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I guard the passages.", 
        "keyword_1": "PASSAGE", 
        "keyword_2": "NO DANGER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "There is no danger.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Well not compared to a dungeon Altar Room!", 
        "name": "The Pass Guard", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Hast thou solved the Altars?", 
        "question_no_answer": "From them a Three Part Key is gained, needed to enter the the Chamber of the Codex!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a guard.", 
        "health": "Top notch.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "A gate guard", 
        "keyword_1": "GATE", 
        "keyword_2": "ABBEY", 
        "keyword_response_1": "To the Abbey.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Here, in the Oak Grove many find the meaning of peace and love!", 
        "name": "A Gate Guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou saturated with Love?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Visit the small Shrine within the Abbey!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then thou need not be here!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a young bard playing a lute.", 
        "health": "Pretty good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a bard, I sing songs.", 
        "keyword_1": "SING SONGS", 
        "keyword_2": "CANDLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Oh, all types.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The Candle of Love is found in a secret place hidden off Lock Lake!", 
        "name": "Derek the Bard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou like this one?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas, it was new.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thanks, I just wrote it!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small but stately child.", 
        "health": "Very well, thank you!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I welcome thee unto the Abbey!", 
        "keyword_1": "OAK ", 
        "keyword_2": "GROVE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A Grove of Oak.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "There four profession types seek Truth!", 
        "name": "Chinup", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou here in search of Love?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Perhaps then the Oak Grove.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Perhaps then the Oak Grove!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall woman.", 
        "health": "Good.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I counsel those who enter the Grove.", 
        "keyword_1": "COUNSEL", 
        "keyword_2": "LOVE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Herein thou may find insights into Love, within thyself or the others here in the Grove.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Ask the others.", 
        "name": "Diane", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Art thou the most loving person?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Strive for Love!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Doubtful!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a solemn bard.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I relate Love and Compassion.", 
        "keyword_1": "LOVE", 
        "keyword_2": "COMPASSION", 
        "keyword_response_1": "When the three combine in eight ways Love alone is Compassion.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Of the eight Avatar attributes Compassion is derived from Love alone.", 
        "name": "Benjamin", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou well?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad...", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Very good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a druid, lost in thought.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I ponder Love and Justice.", 
        "keyword_1": "LOVE", 
        "keyword_2": "JUSTICE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "When three build eight, Truth tempered by Love becomes Justice!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Justice is one of the eight Avatar Virtues and derives from Truth and Love.", 
        "name": "Deirdre", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Art thou?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I see.", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Most good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a hearty tinker.", 
        "health": "Fine", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am thinking of Love's part in Sacrifice.", 
        "keyword_1": "LOVE", 
        "keyword_2": "SACRIFICE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Love of others and the Courage to face even death is Self-Sacrifice.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Sacrifice is built upon the motive of Love and the ability of Courage.", 
        "name": "Thomas", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Thyself?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Shame.", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a solemn ranger.", 
        "health": "Most well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I follow the spiritual path.", 
        "keyword_1": "SPIRITUAL", 
        "keyword_2": "INNER BEING", 
        "keyword_response_1": "My Spirituality is not a religion, but a searching to know and improve my own inner being.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "My being is based on my own Truth, Love and Courage.", 
        "name": "Lastro", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "And thee?", 
        "question_no_answer": "So sad.", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a mumbling beggar.", 
        "health": "Not so good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek salvation.", 
        "keyword_1": "MUMBLING", 
        "keyword_2": "SALVATION", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The...Ankh... spoke to me!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I am but a poor destitute beggar. I have nothing!", 
        "name": "Humlock", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Will you give me some money?", 
        "question_no_answer": "But I am in most dire need!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I would be soooo grateful....", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a bold paladin.", 
        "health": "Just now fully healed!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I solve quests", 
        "keyword_1": "QUESTS", 
        "keyword_2": "HORN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "My last quest took me near Spiritwood.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Some say that the Silver Horn is buried on a small isle off the tip of Spiritwood.", 
        "name": "Malchor", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou on a quest?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Best of luck to thee!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise druid.", 
        "health": "I am getting old and frail.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I hold great wisdom.", 
        "keyword_1": "GREAT WISDOM", 
        "keyword_2": "CANDLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "What dost thou ask of me?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Thou dost need the Candle of Love to enter the Abyss.", 
        "name": "Brother Antos", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou know where to find it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Meditate on Love at our Shrine.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Very good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a stately baron.", 
        "health": "Very well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I rule this province.", 
        "keyword_1": "PROVINCE", 
        "keyword_2": "WORD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Yes, these islands and much more.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I know but one of three syllables-'cor'.", 
        "name": "Sentri", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou know the four cities of Courage?", 
        "question_no_answer": "They are Jhelom, Minoc, Trinsic and Skara Brae.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Very good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a very big Guard.", 
        "health": "Very strong!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Guard the gates, of course.", 
        "keyword_1": "GATE", 
        "keyword_2": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "These are the gates to Serpent Castle.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Guard, watch, protect.", 
        "name": "The Gate Guard.", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou here to find Courage?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then perhaps to become a guard!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then thou art at the right place.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wounded sailor.", 
        "health": "I alone survived the shipwreck.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a sailor.", 
        "keyword_1": "SHIPWRECK", 
        "keyword_2": "WHEEL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The H.M.S. Cape.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "She went down in the deep waters of the bay in the Cape of Heroes!", 
        "name": "Lassorn", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Ever heard of her?", 
        "question_no_answer": "She was a mighty vessel!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "She was a mighty vessel!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a seasoned fighter.", 
        "health": "Just healed.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I fight for Britannia!", 
        "keyword_1": "ABYSS", 
        "keyword_2": "CODEX", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The Great Stygian Abyss holds the codex of ultimate wisdom!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I know little.", 
        "name": "Roark", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou well?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou hast come to the right place.", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then strive to find the secrets of the Abyss.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a ranger engrossed in training.", 
        "health": "Excellent.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am training!", 
        "keyword_1": "TRAINING", 
        "keyword_2": "DUNGEONS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I train so that I might survive the dungeons!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I plan to conquer the secret of the Altar Rooms.", 
        "name": "A Ranger.", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Wimp.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Ask our teacher about the rooms for she knowns much!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "the training master.", 
        "health": "Prime.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I train warriors to fight with Courage!", 
        "keyword_1": "TRAIN", 
        "keyword_2": "ALTAR ROOM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Train well and thy Courage can grow with confidence.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "In the Altar Room of Courage use the Red, Orange, Purple and White Stones! Ask a guard of the Altar Room.", 
        "name": "Shyra", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Wilt thou train?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Pity.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Bravo!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a stern guard.", 
        "health": "Most good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I guard our lord", 
        "keyword_1": "LORD", 
        "keyword_2": "THIS CASTLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Sentri rules this castle.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "This castle is built on Courage.", 
        "name": "A Baronial Guard", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou wish an audience with Sentri?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then do not disturb him.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Granted, enter.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a burly guard.", 
        "health": "Excellent.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "We guard our lord's treasure.", 
        "keyword_1": "TREASURE", 
        "keyword_2": "ALTAR ROOM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "This treasure is not for thee", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Seek out Durham for knowledge of dungeons.", 
        "name": "A Treasure Guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou intend to steal our lord's treasure?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Wise move!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Fool!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a bold fighter.", 
        "health": "Quite well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I fight with Courage!", 
        "keyword_1": "COURAGE", 
        "keyword_2": "BELL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Courage makes kings out of knaves!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The Bell of Courage lies at the bottom of a deep well at sea found at lat-N'A\" long-L'A\"", 
        "name": "Garam", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then train!", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall fighter.", 
        "health": "Fairly well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I quest for glory!", 
        "keyword_1": "QUEST", 
        "keyword_2": "DUNGEONS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I feel that when on a quest my life has purpose!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The Altar Room of Courage gives the Third Part of a Key.", 
        "name": "Durham", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou on a quest?", 
        "question_no_answer": "What a loss.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then thy life has meaning!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a buxom guard.", 
        "health": "So far, so good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I guard this passage.", 
        "keyword_1": "GARAM", 
        "keyword_2": "DURHAM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "He is in the west chamber.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "He is in the east chamber.", 
        "name": "Lori", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Art thou looking for someone?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then be on thy way!", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Who?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a handsome guard.", 
        "health": "So far, so good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I guard this passage.", 
        "keyword_1": "GARAM", 
        "keyword_2": "DURHAM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "He is in the west chamber.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "He is in the east chamber.", 
        "name": "Samuel", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou looking for someone?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then be on thy way!", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Who?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a destitute, stinking beggar.", 
        "health": "I've lost a hand!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I cannot work.", 
        "keyword_1": "LOST A HAND", 
        "keyword_2": "ORBS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "It was eaten by a Zorn.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "An orb of blue light will raise thy strength, dexterity or intelligence, but at a cost!", 
        "name": "Roderick", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wilt thou give me gold?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Stingy!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thou art kind.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise druid.", 
        "health": "Well enough.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I have important information.", 
        "keyword_1": "INFORMATION", 
        "keyword_2": "BELL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "On what subject?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The Bell of Courage is needed to enter the Abyss.", 
        "name": "Sister Antos", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou have it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then ask the fighter Garam, for he knows where it lies!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Very good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a spiny nixie!", 
        "health": "Nice and wet!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I swim the seas!", 
        "keyword_1": "SEAS", 
        "keyword_2": "MANY SHIPS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "There are many ships at the bottom!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A survivor would know where to search.", 
        "name": "Noxum", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou heard of the H.M.S. Cape?", 
        "question_no_answer": "A great ship!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "She had a Magical Wheel that would strengthen her hull!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a beautiful paladin!", 
        "health": "Very well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I welcome thee unto Serpent Castle!", 
        "keyword_1": "SENTRI", 
        "keyword_2": "HEALER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "He is the lord here, take the west passage.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Take the east passage.", 
        "name": "Michelle", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Art thou well?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then thou should visit our healer!", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Very good, perhaps thou seeks Sentri.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a young mage.", 
        "health": "Quite good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek adventure!", 
        "keyword_1": "ADVENTURE", 
        "keyword_2": "GREAT QUEST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Yes, I hope to go on a great quest!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The Quest of the Avatar is noble indeed!", 
        "name": "Mariah", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Art thou on a quest?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Wish thou were!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I wish I could join thee!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a starving journalist.", 
        "health": "I feel fine... if I could just quit smoking!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a writer.", 
        "keyword_1": "WRITER", 
        "keyword_2": "SMOKING", 
        "keyword_response_1": "It's low paid, but glamorous!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Cough...cough...", 
        "name": "Tracie", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Do you smoke?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Don't start!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I can tell by the smell!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a regal paladin.", 
        "health": "Well indeed.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I speak of the Virtues of Honesty!", 
        "keyword_1": "HONESTY", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A few honest men are better than numbers!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The Mantra of the Shrine of Honesty is 'AHM'.", 
        "name": "Cromwell", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou strive to be honest?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Shame!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then you will need the Mantra.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a mystic wizard.", 
        "health": "I've been better", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I live an honest life.", 
        "keyword_1": "HONEST LIFE", 
        "keyword_2": "EVIL FORCES", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Speak the truth and shame the evil forces!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Evil still exists in our hearts and souls!", 
        "name": "Rebelias", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou seek to conquer thine own evil?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Wretch!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "The quest of a lifetime!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a playful child.", 
        "health": "Feeling good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am your friend.", 
        "keyword_1": "FRIEND", 
        "keyword_2": "HONEST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Honest friends are few!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "My friend William knows where the Rune of Honesty is.", 
        "name": "Christen", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Art thou my friend?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I am sad.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "That makes me happy.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a meek shepherd.", 
        "health": "Pretty good.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I am a shepherd.", 
        "keyword_1": "HUMBLE", 
        "keyword_2": "HUMILITY", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Humility is not derived from the direct combination of Truth, Love or Courage.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Humility is to act and be humble.", 
        "name": "Patric the Humble Shepherd", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou totally humble?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Strive to be.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Doubtful!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a dying young wizard.", 
        "health": "I will soon die.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am apprentice to the great wizard Nigel!", 
        "keyword_1": "NIGEL", 
        "keyword_2": "DIE ", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I will soon need to use the spell he calls 'Resurrect'.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Pass on.", 
        "name": "Shazom", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou met Nigel?", 
        "question_no_answer": "He lives at the Lycaeum.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Seek him out for he will teach thee.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise wizard.", 
        "health": "Getting on.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I create tales of Honesty.", 
        "keyword_1": "HONESTY", 
        "keyword_2": "CORRUPTION", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Remember, there is no terror in threats for I am strong in Honesty!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Corruption wins not more than Honesty!", 
        "name": "Shakespeare", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou strive to be honest?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Fool!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Beware corruption!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall mage.", 
        "health": "Been better.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I strive to live an honest life!", 
        "keyword_1": "HONEST LIFE", 
        "keyword_2": "TRUTH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "An honest soul need remember no lies!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Truth is the root of Honesty!", 
        "name": "Browning", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou never lied?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Truth never hurts the teller!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "That seems unlikely!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an elderly woman.", 
        "health": "Tired, so tired.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am an alchemist.", 
        "keyword_1": "ALCHEMIST", 
        "keyword_2": "REAGENTS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I know how best to mix reagents!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A Sleep spell requires Ginseng and Spider Silk!", 
        "name": "Cosima", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou know the best way to mix spells?", 
        "question_no_answer": "The secret's in the reagents!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a hunched, insane looking man!", 
        "health": "Health?", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I move the sun!", 
        "keyword_1": "SUN ", 
        "keyword_2": "MOONS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The moons are my enemies!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "When I die, the world will end!", 
        "name": "Daranor", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Do you believe my story!?!?...", 
        "question_no_answer": "Idiot, you must think I am insane!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then we must fell the moons!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an old gypsy.", 
        "health": "I predict I will be fine today!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a fortune teller. I read palms.", 
        "keyword_1": "PALMS", 
        "keyword_2": "FORTUNES", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Palms tell fortunes!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Give thy palm.", 
        "name": "Inoo", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou wish thy destiny?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Wise choice.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "A great quest will lead thee into the Abyss where the codex awaits!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall mage.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I bear greetings from the fair city of Moonglow.", 
        "keyword_1": "INN ", 
        "keyword_2": "HEALER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "We have an excellent inn.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Our healer is one of the best!", 
        "name": "Calabrini", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou seek an inn or healing?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Perhaps, the Shrine which lies on an isle to the north!", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Which?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a bouncy jester.", 
        "health": "Very good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I earn an honest living - jesting!", 
        "keyword_1": "HONEST", 
        "keyword_2": "JESTING", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Honest labor bears a lovely face!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I love a good jest.", 
        "name": "Dekker", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou art probably a sourpuss!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "We ought to exchange jokes sometime!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a child eating a sandwich.", 
        "health": "Pretty good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Oh, not much.", 
        "keyword_1": "SANDWICH", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "It's a Peanut Butter and Grape Jelly on lightly toasted bread!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Search for the Rune of Honesty by Mariah's gold!", 
        "name": "William", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wouldst thou like a bite?", 
        "question_no_answer": "It's awful yummy!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Yummy, huh!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a battered mage.", 
        "health": "Fading.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I used to search for the Blue Stone.", 
        "keyword_1": "BLUE STONE", 
        "keyword_2": "USE ", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The Stone of Honesty is found on an Altar in the dungeon of Deceit.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It is used within the dungeon Altar Rooms and in the Abyss.", 
        "name": "Tyrone", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wilt thou search?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Hmm.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Know its uses!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "charming bard.", 
        "health": "Good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I play for the people.", 
        "keyword_1": "PLAY", 
        "keyword_2": "COMPASSION", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I play my lute and receive the good wishes of the people.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "If you treat someone else well then they will have reason to do the same.", 
        "name": "Iolo", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Do you like my music?", 
        "question_no_answer": "A shame.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I would join thee!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a charming jester.", 
        "health": "Very well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I dance and sing for the children.", 
        "keyword_1": "DANCE", 
        "keyword_2": "BEGGARS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Dance is good for the soul.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "To give to a beggar shows Compassion.", 
        "name": "Gweno", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Do you give to the needy?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Beggars are thankful for small donations.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small child.", 
        "health": "Very happy.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Singing", 
        "keyword_1": "SINGING", 
        "keyword_2": "HoEyoHeHum", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The song goes: Ho eyo he hum!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It means: Love to one and all!", 
        "name": "A Child", 
        "pronoun": null, 
        "question": "Do you like the song?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then help us spread the word!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a guard.", 
        "health": "Good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I guard the bridge.", 
        "keyword_1": "BRIDGE", 
        "keyword_2": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Across the bridge our people dance and sing!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Yep.", 
        "name": "A Guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Would thou like to join them?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then you have no business across the bridge.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Remember, an open heart is the first step on the path to wisdom! Ask Iolo about it", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a spicy woman.", 
        "health": "Healthy.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a fighting bard.", 
        "keyword_1": "BARD", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Bards know many things.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The Rune of Compassion lies at the end of a hall somewhere in this towne.", 
        "name": "Pepper", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou seek something?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas, I may have been able to help.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "What might that be?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a seasoned fighter.", 
        "health": "Fairly well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I search for the mystery of the magic orbs.", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGIC", 
        "keyword_2": "ORBS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Magic orbs.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A one-handed beggar knows their secrets!", 
        "name": "Thevel", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou seen him?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Find him in Serpent castle for he knows of orbs!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Only he knows the orb's gift!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a drunken fighter.", 
        "health": "And a bottle of...", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Yo ho ho...\u0001and a bottle...\u0001of rum...\u0001hic...", 
        "keyword_1": "STONES", 
        "keyword_2": "RUM ", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The Yellow Stone is in the dungeon Despise...", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Rum... hic...", 
        "name": "Joe", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Give me rum?...", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ah, be a joe!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thanxth...\u0001my friend Joe can help with the Stones...\u0001 hic...", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a bard in green.", 
        "health": "Shhh", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Shhh, I'm playing!", 
        "keyword_1": "SHHH", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Yes, shhh!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The Mantra for the Shrine of Compassion is 'MU'!", 
        "name": "Cricket", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Now wilt thou be quiet?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I am going to call the guards!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thanks.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a cheerful guard.", 
        "health": "I am fully healed.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a guard of course!", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "COMPASSION", 
        "keyword_response_1": "We guards have a lot of Compassion.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "We always say: Let all others' troubles be as thine own!", 
        "name": "A Guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou kill non-evil creatures?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Good.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "That does not show Compassion!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small child.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am learning Compassion.", 
        "keyword_1": "LEARNING", 
        "keyword_2": "COMPASSION", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The solution to ones problems often lies in solving others!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Never care so much for thyself that thou cannot care for others!", 
        "name": "A Child", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Know ye the Mantra of Compassion?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ask Cricket!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tired shepherd.", 
        "health": "Good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I watch over the children.", 
        "keyword_1": "CHILDREN", 
        "keyword_2": "COMPASSION", 
        "keyword_response_1": "It takes a good deal of Compassion to deal with children!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Compassion strengthens the soul as knowledge tempers the mind!", 
        "name": "Shalimar", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Have any kids?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thou dost know what I mean!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an injured person.", 
        "health": "Not so well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I know a terrible secret!", 
        "keyword_1": "SECRET", 
        "keyword_2": "MONDAIN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Mondain's influence has not left the world!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "An artifact remains! I heard at Buccaneer's Den!", 
        "name": "Sebastian", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wilt thou find and destroy it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then ask at the pub there of the skull!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a druid.", 
        "health": "All right.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am looking for Julio.", 
        "keyword_1": "JULIO", 
        "keyword_2": "COMPASSION", 
        "keyword_response_1": "He knows the true nature of Compassion.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Seek out Julio and ask him of Compassion!", 
        "name": "Shapero", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou on the Quest of the Avatar?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Find the Shrine of Compassion east across 2 bridges!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a solemn bard.", 
        "health": "Solemn.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I seek the true nature of things!", 
        "keyword_1": "TRUE NATURE", 
        "keyword_2": "COMPASSION", 
        "keyword_response_1": "All things have a true nature!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Compassion derives itself from unending Love!", 
        "name": "Julio", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou know the true nature of all things?", 
        "question_no_answer": "No mortal can.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thou art a liar and a braggart.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise shepherd.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I escaped Magincia!", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGINCIA", 
        "keyword_2": "PRIDE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Pride was too great in Magincia!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The city was destroyed by Daemons for its Pride!", 
        "name": "Mentor", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou proud?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Pride exists without Truth, Love, or Courage!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "That is not a Virtue!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a poor beggar.", 
        "health": "I fear I shall die of starvation!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I have no job so now I beg!", 
        "keyword_1": "STARVATION", 
        "keyword_2": "BEG ", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I have not eaten in a week!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Please! Help me!", 
        "name": "Sprite", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Wilt thou help me?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I shall starve to death!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "In return, I shall tell thee that Pepper knows of the Rune!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a 6 foot 5, great warrior.", 
        "health": "I am good and strong!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I lead into battle!", 
        "keyword_1": "WARRIOR", 
        "keyword_2": "BATTLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A great warrior is a valiant warrior!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I desire to fight again in battle!", 
        "name": "Geoffrey", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou valiant?", 
        "question_no_answer": "To flee battle shows cowardice!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Perhaps I could someday join thee!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a mysterious warrior.", 
        "health": "Outstanding!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I battle for Lord British!", 
        "keyword_1": "WARRIOR", 
        "keyword_2": "BATTLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Thou must battle long and hard to be a warrior", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Battles are few and too many!", 
        "name": "Lord Robert", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Are you a valiant warrior?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou art a wimp!", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thou dost deserve the Rune, ask Nostro!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a 5 foot pregnant woman.", 
        "health": "Fine, all but the lump in my stomach.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I watch over my sheep.", 
        "keyword_1": "PREGNANT", 
        "keyword_2": "SHEEP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "It's no fun to be pregnant.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I can't stand Sheep!", 
        "name": "Lady Donna", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Why, art thou the father?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thank God!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Wait till I tell my husband!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wounded fighter!", 
        "health": "Poor.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I search the dungeons!", 
        "keyword_1": "DUNGEONS", 
        "keyword_2": "ROOM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I fell in the dungeon 'Destard'.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Therein use the Stones found in the connecting dungeons!", 
        "name": "Bengrod", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou found its Altar Room?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Find it!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "It connects with Covetous, Shame and Hythloth!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a noble fighter.", 
        "health": "Very well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I search for valiant fighters!", 
        "keyword_1": "ALL EVIL", 
        "keyword_2": "KILL NOT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Kill not non-evil creatures, but still always stand thy ground!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Let them flee instead, never flee uninjured!", 
        "name": "Sir William", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou valiant?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I see.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Strive ye to defeat all evil!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a mighty warrior!", 
        "health": "Excellent.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I fight for Valor!", 
        "keyword_1": "VALOR", 
        "keyword_2": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The valiant soul fears not its own visage!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The Mantra need be known, ask Aesop!", 
        "name": "Sir Hrothgar", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou the most valiant of souls?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou should seek the Shrine of Valor!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "This is not likely!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a stern guard.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "We guard the gates and these passages!", 
        "keyword_1": "GATES", 
        "keyword_2": "PASSAGES", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The gates of Jhelom.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "These passages are restricted.", 
        "name": "A Guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "", 
        "question_no_answer": "", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small man.", 
        "health": "Well enough.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I search for Valor!", 
        "keyword_1": "VALOR", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I find that 'tis easy to be brave from a safe distance!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The Mantra of Valor is 'RA' use it in the Shrine on the next isle!", 
        "name": "Aesop", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Know what I mean?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou art brave!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "That's my problem.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a grave fighter.", 
        "health": "So so.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I search the dungeons.", 
        "keyword_1": "DUNGEONS", 
        "keyword_2": "RED STONE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I seek the Red Stone.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It is found on an Altar!", 
        "name": "Gravnor", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou have it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "It lies in the dungeon Destard!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "No wonder I can't find it!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a beautiful mage.", 
        "health": "Well enough.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am locked up in this tower.", 
        "keyword_1": "TOWER", 
        "keyword_2": "CRIMES", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I am being punished for my crimes.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Does not matter, I can help thee!", 
        "name": "Senora", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou have a ship?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then thou dost need a Sextant ask the barkeep for he knows more!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a withering soul.", 
        "health": "Very near death!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I built these passages and they walled me in!", 
        "keyword_1": "PASSAGES", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "This passage runs around the city!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The Rune is buried in a tower!", 
        "name": "Nostro", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wilt thou lead me out?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou art a cad! and I will still follow!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I am saved!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a ranger with a far away look.", 
        "health": "Quite well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek the Inner Light!", 
        "keyword_1": "INNER LIGHT", 
        "keyword_2": "YEW ", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I come from Skara Brae, and am on my way to Yew.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "'tis a city based in the Virtue of Justice!", 
        "name": "Luke", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou been to Skara Brae?", 
        "question_no_answer": "'tis a spiritual city!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "A fine city!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "the housekeeper.", 
        "health": "Good!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am the housekeeper.", 
        "keyword_1": "HOUSEKEEPER", 
        "keyword_2": "ROOMS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I clean the rooms.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "That's a strange one at the end. People often disappear.", 
        "name": "Max", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Is there some problem with thy room?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh, thou had me worried!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I am very sorry, I will correct it right away!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a strange person.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I seek the Stone", 
        "keyword_1": "STONE", 
        "keyword_2": "RED STONE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The Red Stone.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Red is for Valor a Virtue of the Avatar!", 
        "name": "X", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou an Avatar?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then thou shalt need the Red Stone in one Altar Room to get the Third Part of a Key!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Wow!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a valiant warrior.", 
        "health": "Only minor wounds!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I fight battles!", 
        "keyword_1": "BATTLES", 
        "keyword_2": "TRUE VALOR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "True Valor is seen not in the force of arms, but in the force of will!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I display my valor in battle.", 
        "name": "Slithe", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou valiant?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Coward.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then never flee unless the need is dire!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a thin fighter.", 
        "health": "Couldn't be better!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I fight with Valor!", 
        "keyword_1": "VALOR", 
        "keyword_2": "BRAVE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "There is no holier spot of ground than where defeated Valor lies.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Be brave for there is much to dare!", 
        "name": "Timrod", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou brave?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Coward.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Fortune helps the brave!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a quiet druid.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I strive to understand Justice.", 
        "keyword_1": "JUSTICE", 
        "keyword_2": "UNDERSTAND", 
        "keyword_response_1": "True Justice satisfies all, false none.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Let Justice be thy calling, not thy excuse!", 
        "name": "Jaana", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Art thou just?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Many a grave has been unjustly filled in the name of Justice.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall guard.", 
        "health": "Yes.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "To guard the court.", 
        "keyword_1": "COURT", 
        "keyword_2": "JUSTICE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Within this chamber Justice is served.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A good life is inspired by Love and guided by knowledge.", 
        "name": "A Guard", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou have business before the court?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then do not disturb the proceedings!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then enter.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a big guard.", 
        "health": "Fit.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "We guard the jail.", 
        "keyword_1": "MISDEMEANORS", 
        "keyword_2": "FELONIES", 
        "keyword_response_1": "That'll be the left cell.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "That'll be the right hand cell. careful in there!", 
        "name": "A Guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou come to turn thyself in?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Just visiting, eh.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "In which cell dost thou belong, felonies or misdemeanors.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a solemn druid.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I make spells.", 
        "keyword_1": "SPELLS", 
        "keyword_2": "MANDRAKE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I invented quickness!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Mandrake Root is found only in the Fens of the Dead, and in the Bloody Plains where the ground is always damp.", 
        "name": "Calumny", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Can thou cast it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Adept.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "It requires Ash, Ginseng, and Bloodmoss!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise judge.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I decide Justice.", 
        "keyword_1": "JUSTICE", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Justice is Truth in action!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It is hidden well!", 
        "name": "Talfourd", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Can thou honestly claim to be guilty of no crime ever?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then do thy penance in a cell and, with the felon, search ye well.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Doubtful.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a burning fire.", 
        "health": "Bright.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I hold the fabric of the true nature of Justice.", 
        "keyword_1": "JUSTICE", 
        "keyword_2": "FABRIC", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The Virtue of Justice draws its nature from the Principles of Truth and Love!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Of Justice.", 
        "name": "Flamis", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Hast thou always been just?", 
        "question_no_answer": "At least thou art honest.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Unlikely.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a chanting druid.", 
        "health": "Beh... Beh...", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Beh... Beh...", 
        "keyword_1": "BEH...", 
        "keyword_2": "", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Beh... Beh...", 
        "keyword_response_2": "", 
        "name": "Silent", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "", 
        "question_no_answer": "", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise druid.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Welcome thee to Yew, city of Justice!", 
        "keyword_1": "JUSTICE", 
        "keyword_2": "YEW ", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Love no one more than the Truth, for Justice seeks no favors. Temper thy Justice with understanding.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Yes 'tis a fair city!", 
        "name": "Dwp", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou like it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "A pity.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Let it be as thine!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a poor beggar.", 
        "health": "Well treated.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I have sinned.", 
        "keyword_1": "SINNED", 
        "keyword_2": "FELON", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I have gotten chests in the townes and killed non-evil creatures.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "He is a mean, nasty, ugly villain!", 
        "name": "A Poor Beggar.", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Should thou be in with the felon?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Good.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thou art in the wrong cell.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a mean nasty ugly villain!", 
        "health": "Hungry!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I eat people who bug me!", 
        "keyword_1": "VILLAIN", 
        "keyword_2": "PEOPLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "That's me alright!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Like thee!", 
        "name": "Vorpal", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou here to bug me?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Well thou art!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Eat death, scum puppy!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 60
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a sleek ranger.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I search for a home.", 
        "keyword_1": "HOME", 
        "keyword_2": "RANGE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "On the range!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Where the Deer and the Antelope play.", 
        "name": "A Ranger", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Ever heard of such a place?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ah, what'ya have to ruin it for!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Seldom is heard a discouraging word!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an old man.", 
        "health": "I'm old.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I'm questing for the Holy Grail with my son.", 
        "keyword_1": "SON", 
        "keyword_2": "HOLY GRAIL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Junior often helps me.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I've been searching it for a long time!", 
        "name": "Henry Jones", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou questing for something?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I hope thee finish thy quest.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a withered form.", 
        "health": "I am starving and sick.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "See my poor baby, I beg for him.", 
        "keyword_1": "POOR BABY", 
        "keyword_2": "JUST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Oh, no, my baby is dying!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Jaana may join thee!", 
        "name": "Frida", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Wilt thou give me money so that I can get my baby healed?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Evil wretch, curse thee!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thou art kind and just!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a thin man.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I take council.", 
        "keyword_1": "COUNCIL", 
        "keyword_2": "ON JUSTICE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "On Justice.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Justice is hardest to find at the point of a sword, the steel is an agent of Justice, humanity the perpetrator!", 
        "name": "Pinrod", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Fight ye for Justice?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Cad.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good, the druids chant the Mantra!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a big guard.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "To preserve the peace and insure Justice!", 
        "keyword_1": "PEACE", 
        "keyword_2": "JUSTICE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A good life is inspired by Love and guided by Truth!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Justice means not only to punish the bad, but also to reward the good!", 
        "name": "A Guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou always just?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Strive to be!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Unlikely!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wandering druid.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek Justice.", 
        "keyword_1": "JUSTICE", 
        "keyword_2": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Learn at the Shrine!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The Shrine is to the east then north!", 
        "name": "Druid", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou have the Rune?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ask Talfourd for he knows of the Rune.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Now learn the Mantra, and seek the Green Stone in 'Wrong'!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an agile tinker.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I care for the poor.", 
        "keyword_1": "CARE", 
        "keyword_2": "POOR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Self preservation is the first law of nature; Self Sacrifice the highest rule of grace.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Within this house are many poor and destitute souls.", 
        "name": "Julia", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Wilt thou help?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Bum.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I would join thee.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a seasoned blacksmith.", 
        "health": "Quite well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I forge weapons.", 
        "keyword_1": "WEAPONS", 
        "keyword_2": "MYSTIC", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I make the very best!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Ah, yes, the Mystic Weapons, and Armour, my greatest work! Those I gave unto Sir Simon and Lady Tessa.", 
        "name": "Zircon", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Seek thee a weapon?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Hmmm.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Ask at the counter!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a sickly little man.", 
        "health": "I am very sick, help me!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I have none, help me.", 
        "keyword_1": "HELP", 
        "keyword_2": "SICK", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I need money to cure my sickness.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I have terminal leg rot.", 
        "name": "Bob the Beggar", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou any money?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then join me and we can beg together!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then please share it with me!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small muddy girl.", 
        "health": "I am hungry.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I'm an undernourished beggar girl.", 
        "keyword_1": "HUNGRY", 
        "keyword_2": "FOOD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I have not eaten in days.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Oh, thou art a kind soul!", 
        "name": "Linda Sue", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Could thou spare a nibble of food?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh, I see.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I would greatly appreciate that.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a fading man.", 
        "health": "I am barely conscious.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I shall die soon.", 
        "keyword_1": "DIE ", 
        "keyword_2": "CONSCIOUS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I suffer from a tsetse bite!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I will soon sleep forever.", 
        "name": "Gimble", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Could thou spare a gold piece, so I may buy a last drink?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I am saddened.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Remember Azure knows of the Rune!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 40
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a ragged soul.", 
        "health": "Ailing.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "To redeem myself!", 
        "keyword_1": "TO REDEEM", 
        "keyword_2": "SKULL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I will not speak of my sin!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I used it!", 
        "name": "Jude", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "If I help thee, wilt thou swear to only use it at the mouth of the Abyss to destroy it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "It can be found at lat-P'F\" long-M'F\" on the darkest night!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an old ragged man.", 
        "health": "I am old and weak.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a peasant. I hear many things.", 
        "keyword_1": "MANY THINGS", 
        "keyword_2": "STONE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "What does thou wish to know?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The Stone of Sacrifice is Orange in color and used in the Altar Rooms of Love and Courage!", 
        "name": "Alkerion", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Seeketh thou?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": "ERROR_10", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good luck.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a stocky ranger.", 
        "health": "Well enough.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am trying to get a room.", 
        "keyword_1": "ROOM", 
        "keyword_2": "SKARA BRAE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I have travelled clear from Skara Brae.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The Rune of our city is missing!", 
        "name": "Mike Ward", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Know thee of the Rune?", 
        "question_no_answer": "It is not in Skara Brae.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "It is the key to the Shrine of Spirituality!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a teenage boy.", 
        "health": "Fine, thanks.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I give out flowers. Here you are!", 
        "keyword_1": "FLOWERS", 
        "keyword_2": "KIND", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The way I figure it, if thou art kind to others they will have reason to be kind in return!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Yes, give all that thou can unto the needy!", 
        "name": "Alex", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wilt thou give?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a rotund tinker.", 
        "health": "OK.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I welcome thee unto Minoc, city of Sacrifice!", 
        "keyword_1": "SACRIFICE", 
        "keyword_2": "VIRTUE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Self-Sacrifice is a needed Virtue!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Avatars strive to be virtuous.", 
        "name": "Shentis", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou strive for Virtue?", 
        "question_no_answer": "An Avatar thou art not!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then perhaps thou shalt become an Avatar!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a cute bard.", 
        "health": "Very well indeed!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I sing songs!", 
        "keyword_1": "SING", 
        "keyword_2": "SONGS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I sing songs!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Very well, the raven sings,\u0001           the raven saw\u0001           and in the corn\u0001           he sayeth 'CAH'.", 
        "name": "Singsong", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou like it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad...", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thanks.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a meek shepherd.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I stand here and think.", 
        "keyword_1": "THINK", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Oh, just about things.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Listen to the bard's song for in its verse lies the key!", 
        "name": "Damon", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Can't a man just think to himself?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh, yes I can thou bandersnatch!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Well I hope so!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 10
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a happy tinker.", 
        "health": "O.K. I guess.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "This and that.", 
        "keyword_1": "THIS", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "And that...", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The Rune of Sacrifice is hard to get. It lies within the fires of the forge!", 
        "name": "Mischief", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Hast thou the Rune?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Return when thou dost find it!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then ask Alkerion of the Stone!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tinker at the table.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I carve runes.", 
        "keyword_1": "CARVE RUNES", 
        "keyword_2": "SACRIFICE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I carve Runes for passage into the Shrines!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Ask my sister, Mischief.", 
        "name": "Azure", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou seek a Rune?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I see.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Which?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wandering tinker.", 
        "health": "Been better.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek the wisdom of the Shrine of Sacrifice.", 
        "keyword_1": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "But first I need the Mantra!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I am told that a hidden shepherd knows the Mantra.", 
        "name": "Merida", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Know ye the Mantra?", 
        "question_no_answer": "The Shrine is on a lake to the east!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a massive guard.", 
        "health": "Quite.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "To guard of course.", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "LIFE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I often wonder if I will ever have to give my life in the line of duty.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "One life for many!", 
        "name": "A Guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Understand my dilemma?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Of course, if it came down to it, I hope I would do it!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "handsome fighter.", 
        "health": "Very well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am towne leader", 
        "keyword_1": "TOWNE LEADER", 
        "keyword_2": "HONOR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "'tis an Honor!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It gives life meaning!", 
        "name": "Dupre", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou try to live honorably?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Fool!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "It is a constant quest. Honor is like finely polished armour. Without constant care, it will soon tarnish!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a mystic wizard.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I create magical fields.", 
        "keyword_1": "FIELDS", 
        "keyword_2": "NIGHTSHADE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Poison is my favorite.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Nightshade may be found only near lat-J'F\", long-C'O\" only on the darkest of nights!", 
        "name": "Virgil", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "'tis it thine?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Well I don't care!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Bravo!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a sleepy fighter.", 
        "health": "Tired.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I drink a toast to Honor!", 
        "keyword_1": "HONOR", 
        "keyword_2": "NOTHING", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Nothing is left when Honor is lost!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Yes, take Honor from me and my life is done!", 
        "name": "Publius", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou strive to live an honorable life?", 
        "question_no_answer": "No Honor, no meaning!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Honor gives greatness.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a bony skeleton.", 
        "health": "What do you mean?", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I hail from dungeon deep.", 
        "keyword_1": "DUNGEON DEEP", 
        "keyword_2": "PURPLE STONE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I come from the dungeon 'Shame'!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I have seen the Purple Stone used in the Altars of Truth and Courage!", 
        "name": "Skitle", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Ever been there?", 
        "question_no_answer": "It holds items thou shalt need.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an ugly sailor.", 
        "health": "A bit waterlogged.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I sail the the seas of Britannia!", 
        "keyword_1": "SEAS", 
        "keyword_2": "SEXTANT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "My specialty is navigation!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Go to the pub in Jhelom and ask of Sextants.", 
        "name": "Sailor Sam", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Is it thy specialty?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou must not own a Sextant, eh?", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good show mate!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a dignified paladin.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I search for Honor.", 
        "keyword_1": "HONOR", 
        "keyword_2": "DIGNITY", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Dignity consists not in possessing Honors, but in deserving them.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Honor no one, but Honor itself!", 
        "name": "Aristotle", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou honorable at all times?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Strive to be as such.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "That is impressive.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a cowering child.", 
        "health": "Scared!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I ran from the bull!", 
        "keyword_1": "BULL", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A big one, with long, pointy horns!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It is buried in the southwest corner of towne.", 
        "name": "Terrin", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Is it gone yet?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Save me!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Whew, I thought it would get me!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a strong paladin.", 
        "health": "Extra good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am the welcomer.", 
        "keyword_1": "WELCOMER", 
        "keyword_2": "HONOR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Yes, welcome to Trinsic, city of Honor!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Wisdom on the Virtue of Honor is found throughout this towne.", 
        "name": "Rigmore", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou seek this wisdom?", 
        "question_no_answer": "This is the wrong place!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Enter and find thy path.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a scruffy merchant.", 
        "health": "A bit ragged out.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "A trade in rumors.", 
        "keyword_1": "RUMORS", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "About what?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "There is a small child who knew named... Terrin.", 
        "name": "Winthrop", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou know him?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Find him and ask of the Rune!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Ask him of the Rune.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall wizard.", 
        "health": "Fully healed.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I cast spells.", 
        "keyword_1": "SPELLS", 
        "keyword_2": "MANDRAKE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Spells of great power.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Ask at the Folley tavern of Mandrake.", 
        "name": "Swindrik", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou cast spells of great power?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Dost thou know their main ingredient?", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "What is the most powerful reagent?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a searching paladin!", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek entry to the Shrine of Honor!", 
        "keyword_1": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The Mantra is 'SUMM'.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A man named Winthrop knows of the Rune!", 
        "name": "Kline", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Know ye the two requirements to enter and use the Shrine?", 
        "question_no_answer": "What dost thou think?", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "What are they?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a shining paladin.", 
        "health": "Superb.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am warlord of Trinsic.", 
        "keyword_1": "WARLORD", 
        "keyword_2": "QUEST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I have solved many quests!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The solving of quests brings ye Honor!", 
        "name": "Lexington", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Strive ye for Honor?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then solve quests but attack not non-evil creatures, and get not others gold!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a soulful fighter.", 
        "health": "Tired.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek a place to rest.", 
        "keyword_1": "REST", 
        "keyword_2": "QUEST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I have quested long and hard.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I seek enlightenment at the Shrine of Honor!", 
        "name": "Dergin", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou enlightened in Honor?", 
        "question_no_answer": "The Shrine lies to the south and west beyond the swamps!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a big guard.", 
        "health": "Excellent.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "We guard the gate.", 
        "keyword_1": "GATE", 
        "keyword_2": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Into and out of Trinsic.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "'tis an honorable job!", 
        "name": "A Guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou strive to bring Honor upon the peers?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Dolt.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Dupre, the leader of our towne, joins many honorable quests!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wandering mage.", 
        "health": "Adequate.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek the skeleton!", 
        "keyword_1": "SKELETON", 
        "keyword_2": "GREAT SECRET", 
        "keyword_response_1": "It knows a great secret,", 
        "keyword_response_2": "about the purple stone of honor!", 
        "name": "Quix", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou have the Purple Stone?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Seek it for it is very useful!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Use it wisely!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a strong guard.", 
        "health": "Guarded.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "To guard.", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "STRONG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Guarding.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Guard", 
        "name": "A Guard", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "", 
        "question_no_answer": "", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "", 
        "turns_away_prob": 40
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a solemn ranger.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek the Inner Light.", 
        "keyword_1": "INNER LIGHT", 
        "keyword_2": "GREAT TRUTH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I seek the \"One Great Truth\"!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "That which lies within the Codex!", 
        "name": "Shamino", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou seek this \"Truth\"?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas.", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "Some things take forever, but brick by brick mountains can be built!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an injured man.", 
        "health": "I am grievously wounded.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek the spiritual path.", 
        "keyword_1": "SPIRITUAL", 
        "keyword_2": "WOUNDED", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Spiritual is stronger than any material force.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Nothing can bring thee peace but the triumph of Principles!", 
        "name": "Emerson", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou good in spirit?", 
        "question_no_answer": "An evil path!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "A good path.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall ranger.", 
        "health": "I am alive.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I carry the light within my heart.", 
        "keyword_1": "LIGHT", 
        "keyword_2": "PHILOSOPHY", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The light of philosophy.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "In philosophical minds the familiar excites wonder!", 
        "name": "Santayana", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou always tread the right path?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Few can, but strive to do so!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Doubtful!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a very small wizard.", 
        "health": "Superior!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I cast great big spells!", 
        "keyword_1": "SPELLS", 
        "keyword_2": "NIGHTSHADE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I can cast: Jinx, Kill, and View!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Yes, ask the barkeep at 'The Axe-n-Grog' in Vesper about nightshade.", 
        "name": "Presto", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou know what these spells have in common?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Guess!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "What?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a hungry beggar.", 
        "health": "I am not at all well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I beg for food and money.", 
        "keyword_1": "FOOD", 
        "keyword_2": "MONEY", 
        "keyword_response_1": "To eat!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "To buy food!", 
        "name": "Granted", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Wilt thou give me food or money?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Jerk!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "In return I will tell thee that the Ankh knows of the Rune and my friend Ambule knows the Mantra!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a radiant ranger.", 
        "health": "I am fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am reading the wizard's journal.", 
        "keyword_1": "JOURNAL", 
        "keyword_2": "WHITE STONE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "It tells of the White Stone.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It is no longer in the dungeon Hythloth, it is gone!", 
        "name": "Mitre", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Wilt thou try to recover it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Ask of the Stone at the Tap in Trinsic!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a great philosopher.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I teach.", 
        "keyword_1": "TEACH", 
        "keyword_2": "ONE NOBLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "When one has pity on all living creatures then is one noble.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "If one speaks or acts with pure thought, happiness will follow like a shadow that never leaves.", 
        "name": "Buddha", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "", 
        "question_no_answer": "", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a skilled ranger.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I strive along the path.", 
        "keyword_1": "PATH", 
        "keyword_2": "JOURNEY", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Success is a journey, not a destination.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "May thou always desire more than thou can accomplish!", 
        "name": "Michaelangelo", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou far along the path?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Fear not thou shalt be.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "This is good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a short dumpy man with a book.", 
        "health": "I am fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a teacher, I enrich young minds.", 
        "keyword_1": "TEACHER", 
        "keyword_2": "WORD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I teach of the Abyss.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Seek Zair the Wise in Paws for more on the Word.", 
        "name": "Romasco", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Know ye of the Abyss?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Learn!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "A Word of Passage is needed at the last gate!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise mage.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I write magic.", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGIC", 
        "keyword_2": "BELIEVING", 
        "keyword_response_1": "One lives by believing in something.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Great discoveries are made by those whose feelings run ahead of their thinking.", 
        "name": "Carlyle", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou believe in magic?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I see.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Iceball needs Pearl and Mandrake Root!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise bard.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I write stories.", 
        "keyword_1": "STORIES", 
        "keyword_2": "SPIRIT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Stories are good for the  spirit!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Remember, no one is useless in this world who lightens the burdens of others!", 
        "name": "Dickens", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou good in nature?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I see.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Be sure thy net good well exceeds thy net evil!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a Galiant fighter.", 
        "health": "Excellent!", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I quest.", 
        "keyword_1": "QUEST", 
        "keyword_2": "DANGEROUS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Many quests are very dangerous!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I am not afraid of tomorrow I, have seen yesterday and I love today.", 
        "name": "White", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou fearless in all Things?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Danger is real!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Boastful fool!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a Silver Ankh.", 
        "health": "Strong.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I keep the secret of the Rune.", 
        "keyword_1": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_2": "OM  ", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Mantra?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Search for the Rune of Spirituality in the treasure chamber of Britannia!", 
        "name": "The Ankh of Spirituality", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Hast thou found the Shrine?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Enter the gate of full moons!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a grimy beggar.", 
        "health": "So-so.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I beg for but for a single gold piece!", 
        "keyword_1": "BEGGAR", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Oh, please... Oh, please...", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Ask the child named Barren.", 
        "name": "Ambule", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Wilt thou please give me a gold piece?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Stingy, I know thou hast many!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Dear kind soul.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small child.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "No job.", 
        "keyword_1": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_2": "", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I know it well, it is 'OM'.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "", 
        "name": "Barren", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "", 
        "question_no_answer": "", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a ghostly figure.", 
        "health": "I am many years dead.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I haunt this inn!", 
        "keyword_1": "HAUNT", 
        "keyword_2": "WHITE STONE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The quest is not complete!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The White Stone sits atop the Serpent's Spine. It can only be reached by one who floats within the clouds.", 
        "name": "Isaac", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou on the quest?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Hope!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a shepherd.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "A survivor.", 
        "keyword_1": "SURVIVOR", 
        "keyword_2": "PRIDE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Magincia was destroyed by its Pride.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Pride flourishes in the absence of Truth, Love and Courage.", 
        "name": "Katrina", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Art thou proud?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Humility is the Virtue that must overcome Pride!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thy efforts are meaningless.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a shadowy ghost.", 
        "health": "Undead in search of peace.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I haunt Magincia", 
        "keyword_1": "PEACE", 
        "keyword_2": "SPIRITS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Peace I can never find, forever banished unto the realm of earthbound spirits.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Be not proud of thy little deeds lest ye too fall from the light!", 
        "name": "Ghostly", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "", 
        "question_no_answer": "", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a jabbering skeleton.", 
        "health": "Most superb.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a nobleman of great birth.", 
        "keyword_1": "NOBLEMAN", 
        "keyword_2": "", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Me and my brother are the last two of the great Meridid family.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "", 
        "name": "Skullface", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Thou hast heard of us of course, yes?", 
        "question_no_answer": "You must not be from near these parts!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I thought so.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small ghost.", 
        "health": "Feeling a bit translucent.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "To haunt this shop.", 
        "keyword_1": "HAUNT", 
        "keyword_2": "PRIDE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A lot of haunting goes on 'round here.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Seek ye the Mantra for Humility, ask ye Heywood!", 
        "name": "Casperin", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Know thee why?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Pride!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Pride is the surest measure of goals never attained!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall ghost.", 
        "health": "Been better.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "Oh, I just hang around!", 
        "keyword_1": "HANG AROUND", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I was hung for my sin of Pride!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The Mantra for Pride, being the antithesis of Humility, is 'MUL'.", 
        "name": "Faultless", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Art thou proud?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Pride is evil's favorite sin!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "A grave sin!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall ghost.", 
        "health": "As well as can be expected.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "Haunt eternally.", 
        "keyword_1": "HAUNT", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Pride goeth before, shame cometh after!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Faultless knows the Mantra of Pride ask him!", 
        "name": "Heywood", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Art thou proud?", 
        "question_no_answer": "A proud soul surely knows not its worth!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thou shalt find shame!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a skinny skeleton.", 
        "health": "A bit on the thin side.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I rattle my bones.", 
        "keyword_1": "BONES", 
        "keyword_2": "PRIDE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I did value myself far too greatly, that Pride was my downfall.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A terrible thing!", 
        "name": "Slim", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Art thou always humble?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Take no Pride in Humility, lest ye destroy it!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Doubtful.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a crumbling skeleton.", 
        "health": "A bit bony.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I once held the Silver Horn.", 
        "keyword_1": "SILVER HORN", 
        "keyword_2": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The Silver Horn must be used to pass the daemon guard of the Shrine.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Wierdrum has been to the Shrine of Humility!", 
        "name": "Banter", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Seek ye the Horn?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Ask Demitry!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a thin skeleton.", 
        "health": "'bout the same as yesterday.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I rattle my bones.", 
        "keyword_1": "BONES", 
        "keyword_2": "HORN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Bones, them bones, them dry bones...", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The queen of Love has a lady in waiting, she can tell thee more of the Horn!", 
        "name": "Demitry", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Art thou dead?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Watch out for Nate!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Ah, too bad!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "rattling bones.", 
        "health": "Haunted.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I haunt, and I haunt, and I haunt!", 
        "keyword_1": "HAUNT", 
        "keyword_2": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A haunting job takes more than a lifetime, it takes forever!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Yes, I have been to the Shrine, it lies on the north bank in the isle of the Abyss!", 
        "name": "Wierdrum", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "", 
        "question_no_answer": "", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a dumpy ghost.", 
        "health": "Hic...", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I was once a powerful merchant!", 
        "keyword_1": "MERCHANT", 
        "keyword_2": "GREAT POWER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "My wealth was boundless, I held great power!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A proud soul surely knows not it's worth!", 
        "name": "Boozer", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Dost thou see?", 
        "question_no_answer": "The world goes on without me.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "The world goes on without me.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a fat skeleton.", 
        "health": "Couldn't be better.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I run this shop.", 
        "keyword_1": "SHOP", 
        "keyword_2": "SPOILED", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Why, the food shop of course.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Well, we're expecting more any day!", 
        "name": "Bulbous", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Can I interest thee in some rations?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I sell only the very best.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Hmmm, our stock seems to have spoiled....", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a weeping skeleton.", 
        "health": "Been better.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I regret.", 
        "keyword_1": "REGRET", 
        "keyword_2": "HUMBLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I was proud, strip thyself of conceits, only the humble are pure!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The root from which all Virtues grow!", 
        "name": "Splot", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Dost thou seek purity?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Fool!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then ask the snake of the Rune and Stone!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a blue ghost.", 
        "health": "Not well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I now try to understand Humility.", 
        "keyword_1": "HUMILITY", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The first test of a great soul is Humility!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Ask the snake of the Rune, just before it strikes!", 
        "name": "Ruskin", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Dost thou seek to know Humility?", 
        "question_no_answer": "A shame.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thou shalt need the Rune!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a mean looking viper!", 
        "health": "Bloodthirsty!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I bring death to all life in Magincia!", 
        "keyword_1": "STONE", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Those who seek the Black Stone need ask at the Pub in Britain!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The sacred Rune of Humility vanished from this city. Ask Barren in Paws!", 
        "name": "Nate", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "", 
        "question_no_answer": "", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a horrible ghastly devil!", 
        "health": "Devilish!", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I welcome thee to Magincia! Proud city of the high seas!", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGINCIA", 
        "keyword_2": "", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Magincia fell unto the realm of darkness for the foundation of their Virtue was ill-placed in Pride!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "", 
        "name": "Virtuebane", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Art thou proud?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ah.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a very big guard.", 
        "health": "Excellent.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am the chief guard in the  village of Paws!", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "TROUBLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Paws is a great village and we keep it safe!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Pirates come from an isle to the east!", 
        "name": "Wilmoore", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou mean to cause trouble?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Good.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then thou had best leave!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tough girl.", 
        "health": "Right good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am the stable hand.", 
        "keyword_1": "STABLE HAND", 
        "keyword_2": "SMITH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I saw the way ya dealt with ol' Red Eye!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The talking horse!", 
        "name": "Francesca", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Ya haven't come to steal a horse I hope?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then must be to see Smith!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Well the master ain't gonna like that much!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall burly man.", 
        "health": "Fine, thanks.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I'm a lumberjack, ya.", 
        "keyword_1": "LUMBERJACK", 
        "keyword_2": "AXE ", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Wit' my axe, I can chop'm down quick, ya.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It's a big axe, ya.", 
        "name": "Sven", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art ya a lumberjack?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Build up those arms, ya!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good for you, ya.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a man of many years.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I've been near the Codex!", 
        "keyword_1": "CODEX", 
        "keyword_2": "WORD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Its secrets are boundless!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A Three Part Key and a Word of Passage are needed to enter the Chamber. Ask my brother beyond Lock Lake of the word!", 
        "name": "Zair the Wise", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Seen it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Seek it!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Wow!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a very large woman.", 
        "health": "Stronger every day!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am the barmaid. I serve the grog!", 
        "keyword_1": "GROG", 
        "keyword_2": "FINEST BREW", 
        "keyword_response_1": "We have the finest grog in Britannia!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "We serve only Folley on tap!", 
        "name": "Sal", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou favor Folley?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad, it's the best!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "A great mug if I may say so!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a young mage!", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek the wisdom of magic.", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGIC", 
        "keyword_2": "MASTER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "My master knows the Gate Travel spell!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "My master is Mentorian.", 
        "name": "Jingles", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou know him?", 
        "question_no_answer": "He lives in a hidden village in Lock Lake reachable only by ship, ask of the Gate spell!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall muscular knight.", 
        "health": "Tired and hungry but always faithful.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I serve Lord British.", 
        "keyword_1": "FAITHFUL", 
        "keyword_2": "QUEST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I quest always for Britannia!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "My quest is to defeat the evils of the world.", 
        "name": "Sir Hobie", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "'tis thy quest also?", 
        "question_no_answer": "A shame it is!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "We are as one.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small druid.", 
        "health": "A bit hungry.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am here to buy food.", 
        "keyword_1": "FOOD", 
        "keyword_2": "BEST RATIONS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Yes, I hear they have the best rations here.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Rations are used in dungeons.", 
        "name": "Damsel", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou travel in the depths?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Probably a wimp.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "In the great castle there is a secret entrance!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a meek shepherd.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I just sit here.", 
        "keyword_1": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_2": "", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Around there in the nook of the mountains!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "", 
        "name": "Wheatpin", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou looking for something?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I see.", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "What?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a hooded ranger.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I travel the land.", 
        "keyword_1": "LAND", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Britannia.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Search the hills in the south-east corner of town!", 
        "name": "Barren", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou dim?", 
        "question_no_answer": "We shall see.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I thought so.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small girl.", 
        "health": "Good, thanks.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "What's a job?", 
        "keyword_1": "", 
        "keyword_2": "", 
        "keyword_response_1": "", 
        "keyword_response_2": "", 
        "name": "Pix", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "And thee?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad.", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise lord.", 
        "health": "I am fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am the keeper.", 
        "keyword_1": "KEEPER", 
        "keyword_2": "MYSTIC", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Of what I cannot say!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Mystics can be found by an eight parts Avatar!", 
        "name": "Sir Simon", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou attained enlightenment in all eight Virtues?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "The Mystic Armour lies in the center of the Oak Grove!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise lady.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am the keeper.", 
        "keyword_1": "KEEPER", 
        "keyword_2": "MYSTIC", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I cannot say.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Mystics can be found by an eight parts Avatar!", 
        "name": "Lady Tessa", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Hast thou attained enlightenment in all eight Virtues?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "The Mystic Weapons lie in the training room of Serpent Castle!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a short jester.", 
        "health": "Jolly good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am here to serve thee.", 
        "keyword_1": "TO SERVE", 
        "keyword_2": "DANCE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Well, I can dance and sing!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "And sing, tra la la...", 
        "name": "Asemly", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Does that interest thee?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Well then, I guess I'm no help at all then.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a singing bard.", 
        "health": "Quite well indeed!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I sing of Britannia.", 
        "keyword_1": "BRITANNIA", 
        "keyword_2": "EARTH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Britannia is a land so fair, to other lands I would not dare!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I hope someday thou may return!", 
        "name": "Little Jon", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "I hear that thou art from another world?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Just a rumor.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "What is it called?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a white stallion.", 
        "health": "Good, good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Oh, not much.", 
        "keyword_1": "", 
        "keyword_2": "", 
        "keyword_response_1": "", 
        "keyword_response_2": "", 
        "name": "Smith", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "", 
        "question_no_answer": "", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a mean looking guard.", 
        "health": "What's it to ya, scumpuppy!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "We guard the bridge slime!", 
        "keyword_1": "BRIDGE SLIME", 
        "keyword_2": "", 
        "keyword_response_1": "This bridge, ya stupid jerk!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "", 
        "name": "Roofus", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou a wise &##!?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then just buzz off!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thou had best ditch it then!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall, muscular, impressive guard.", 
        "health": "Very hungry!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a guard.", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "VERY HUNGRY", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I guard the city!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Yes, I am very hungry!", 
        "name": "Rankbreath", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou here to feed me?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then thou had better run!!!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I am grateful.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a scruffy sailor.", 
        "health": "Salty.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a sailor!", 
        "keyword_1": "SAILOR", 
        "keyword_2": "LIFE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Oh, a sailor's life is the life for me,", 
        "keyword_response_2": "As I sail across the bounding sea!", 
        "name": "Sailor", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "The rest?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "And never ever do I worry 'bout the weather, for the weather never ever did a thing for me!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall sailor.", 
        "health": "Good enough, eh!", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I'm a pirate matey!", 
        "keyword_1": "PIRATE MATEY", 
        "keyword_2": "RAID", 
        "keyword_response_1": "We raid the coasts of Britannia, fun eh!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Pillage and burn!", 
        "name": "Silver John", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou a pirate?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou had best leave this place 'fore there's any trouble!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good matey!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a nimble thief.", 
        "health": "As good as I need be!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "What's it to thee?", 
        "keyword_1": "NIMBLE THIEF", 
        "keyword_2": "CLEVER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Yea, and clever too.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Thou dost ask too many questions!", 
        "name": "Slysam", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou a thief?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Just as I thought", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Oh, I'd better watch out!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 10
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a solemn ranger.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I travel.", 
        "keyword_1": "TRAVEL", 
        "keyword_2": "THING", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The lands of Britannia.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It's the Skull of Mondain the Wizard! Be warned that if thou dost ever use the Skull, except to destroy it, all thy Virtues will be lost!", 
        "name": "Ragnar", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou here looking for information?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then buzz off.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "On what?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 10
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a slinky mage.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a sorceress", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGIC", 
        "keyword_2": "SLEEP SPELL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "How about the Sleep spell...\u0001sleep...\u0001sleep....", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A Sleep spell requires Silk and Ginseng!\u0001sleep...\u0001sleep...\u0001sleep...", 
        "name": "Seanna", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "My dear friend, may I help you?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ah", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "How about with thy magic?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a sneaky thief!", 
        "health": "Very well!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "At thy service!", 
        "keyword_1": "SERVICE", 
        "keyword_2": "HYTHLOTH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "How about information?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The dungeon Hythloth can only be reached by a secret entrance in the great castle.", 
        "name": "Jeremy James Scirlock", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou seek a special dungeon?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I cannot help thee.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Which?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a mage dressed all in black.", 
        "health": "Dark indeed.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I use black magic!", 
        "keyword_1": "BLACK MAGIC", 
        "keyword_2": "MIX", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I cast powerful Missile magicspells.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Iceball requires Black Pearl and Mandrake Root!", 
        "name": "Starlight", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou should try my mix of reagents!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a big fat troll.", 
        "health": "Shove it!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Aw, buzz off!", 
        "keyword_1": "IT", 
        "keyword_2": "", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Thy face!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "", 
        "name": "Brigant", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Did thou hear me?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I said shove it!", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then do it!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 80
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an ugly orc!", 
        "health": "Good'n smelly.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I smuggle black market items.", 
        "keyword_1": "ITEMS", 
        "keyword_2": "", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Magic Keys, Magic Gems, that sort of thing.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "", 
        "name": "Boris", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Dost thou need such an item?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ah well, maybe next time.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I just gave the guild shop a new supply!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a towering wizard.", 
        "health": "Adequate.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I must warn thee!", 
        "keyword_1": "WARN", 
        "keyword_2": "DOOM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "To step into those woods will seal thy doom!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "In there lies the dark side, enter not!", 
        "name": "Ignap", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Shalt thou go on?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Wise decision!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Evil shall consume thee!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall pirate with a green beard!", 
        "health": "Jolly good mate!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I'm buying armour for my crew!", 
        "keyword_1": "ARMOUR", 
        "keyword_2": "", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I hope to get some Magical Plate!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "", 
        "name": "Green Beard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Is it true that Mystic Armour isn't sold anywhere?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Where is it sold?", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Too bad!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a plump merchant.", 
        "health": "Great!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I sell wine!", 
        "keyword_1": "WINE", 
        "keyword_2": "VINTAGES", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I have some good vintages.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I own my own vineyards, they are on an isle northeast of here!", 
        "name": "Marsor", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou like wine?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Don't know what thou art missing!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Ah, then join me in a glass!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a jolly old soul.", 
        "health": "Jolly good, thanks.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a tinker by trade.", 
        "keyword_1": "TINKER", 
        "keyword_2": "MACHINERY", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I create projectile machinery.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Primarily ship cannons!", 
        "name": "Dancek", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou own a ship!", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou really should get one!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good odds I built the cannons!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a cowering man.", 
        "health": "O.K. for now.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am hiding.", 
        "keyword_1": "HIDING", 
        "keyword_2": "SOMETHING", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I know something others want!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I... I...", 
        "name": "Sniflet", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wilt thou promise to use it only to aid the powers of good?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh, no.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "The lighter than air device that was stolen lies near the dungeon Hythloth!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall mage.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "We welcome thee to Vesper.", 
        "keyword_1": "WELCOME", 
        "keyword_2": "VESPER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Welcome, unto Vesper!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Yes, Vesper is a fair village.\t", 
        "name": "Twin Gates", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou come a long way?", 
        "question_no_answer": "We are honored by the visit of one on the quest!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "We are honored by the visit of one on the quest!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a hulk.", 
        "health": "Ug, me tough!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Ug, me tough!", 
        "keyword_1": "TOUGH", 
        "keyword_2": "UG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Ug, me tough!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Me tough!", 
        "name": "Guard", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Ug, thee tough?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ug, me tough!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Ug, thee tough!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a meek shepherd.", 
        "health": "Well for now.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I can help thee!", 
        "keyword_1": "HELP", 
        "keyword_2": "SKULL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I know of the Skull of Mondain the Wizard!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "To use it for any reason is a sign of great evil, and no Virtue!", 
        "name": "Servile", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou heard of it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "It is an evil artifact!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "It is an evil artifact!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "short rotund man, with a hat and vest.", 
        "health": "I am fine, thank thee.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Traveling dan, the tinker man.", 
        "keyword_1": "TINKER MAN", 
        "keyword_2": "TRAVELING", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I am here to repair goods at the guild shop.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I know the world is round!", 
        "name": "Traveling Dan", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Been to the guild shop?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Best prices!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Great selection!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a sturdy peasant.", 
        "health": "I'm pooped.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a serf.", 
        "keyword_1": "SERF", 
        "keyword_2": "WORK", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Serfs work hard for little pay!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I work the fields for my master!", 
        "name": "Balthasar", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou have a master?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou art lucky indeed!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I hope he or she is a kind one!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small man.", 
        "health": "I am fully healed.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek Humility.", 
        "keyword_1": "HUMILITY", 
        "keyword_2": "PRIDE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "When the 3 Principles of Virtue combine in eight ways Pride has no Virtue!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "To be proud is not a Virtue, and so Magincia was destroyed! Humility is the Virtue that remains!", 
        "name": "Plain", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "", 
        "question_no_answer": "", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a slender shepherdess.", 
        "health": "I am fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek the Shrine.", 
        "keyword_1": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_2": "HUMILITY", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The Shrine of Humility!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The Shrine lies on the north bank of the isle of the Abyss and is guarded by endless hoards of Daemons!", 
        "name": "Simple", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Know the isle?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Southeast of Britannia!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a fair woman.", 
        "health": "I am doing well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I do humble works.", 
        "keyword_1": "HUMBLE WORKS", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I can help thee with the Mantra!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Since Humility is the opposite of Pride, so is its Mantra!", 
        "name": "Gem", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Know ye the Mantra of Pride?", 
        "question_no_answer": "When thou dost, reverse it!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then reverse it for Humility!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise shepherd.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am but a humble shepherd.", 
        "keyword_1": "SHEPHERD", 
        "keyword_2": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I am on a pilgrimage unto the Shrine of Humility!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It is on the dark island!", 
        "name": "Joseph", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Did thou know that there is no Shrine of Pride?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Pride is not a Virtue of the Avatar!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Very good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a beautiful and impressive guard.", 
        "health": "I am well enough!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I shall warn thee against taking this gold!", 
        "keyword_1": "WARN", 
        "keyword_2": "THIS GOLD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "It is not thine!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It is not thine!", 
        "name": "Friday", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou intend to take it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "That is good.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "That would not reflect well upon thy Virtues!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a solemn ranger.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I teach of the Shrines.", 
        "keyword_1": "SHRINES", 
        "keyword_2": "", 
        "keyword_response_1": "One must visit each Shrine for 1, 2 & 3 cycles each for thy paths to be clear!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "", 
        "name": "Randal", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou visit them often?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Make that the first goal along thy path to Avatarhood!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Very good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise man.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I give wise counsel.", 
        "keyword_1": "WISE COUNSEL", 
        "keyword_2": "VIRTUE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Strive ye to know and develop the Virtue within thee.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The Seer Hawkwind should be consulted often for he can see within thee!", 
        "name": "Dirgen", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou shalt surely stray from the path!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a funny jester.", 
        "health": "I've a slight tickle!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Thou thinks I'm funny!", 
        "keyword_1": "FUNNY", 
        "keyword_2": "NATE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I dare thee to ask me about Nate the snake!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Well, it's a long story and we haven't the time.", 
        "name": "Shazbot", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Don't thou?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ah, too bad, I thought I was.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Well good, I try to be!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a slender youth.", 
        "health": "I am very powerful!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am an apprentice mage!", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGE", 
        "keyword_2": "CALUMNY", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I am the Calumny's favorite!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "He lives in Yew!", 
        "name": "Flatbush", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou been to Yew?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Calumny knows the Quickness spell! Seek him out!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Calumny knows the Quickness spell!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a bold paladin.", 
        "health": "I am fully healed!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I travel these fair lands to spread the Virtues!", 
        "keyword_1": "VIRTUES", 
        "keyword_2": "", 
        "keyword_response_1": "To know thy progress on the paths of Virtue one must visit the Seer Hawkwind often!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "", 
        "name": "Corkrin", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou do this?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou must or thou may stray!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall nimble man.", 
        "health": "I am very well!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a thief, I like to borrow!", 
        "keyword_1": "BORROW", 
        "keyword_2": "HORSES", 
        "keyword_response_1": "My favorite things to borrow are horses!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "You can steal horses in the towne Paws!", 
        "name": "Dyka", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou a thief?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Likely, thou art a wimp!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Watch out for the bull in the corral!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small boy.", 
        "health": "I am fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I know how to enter the Abyss!", 
        "keyword_1": "ABYSS", 
        "keyword_2": "SHIP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The Abyss may only be approached by ship!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The ship must have a magically strengthened hull!", 
        "name": "Allen", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou such a vessel?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ask Blissful of the Abyss.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Ask Blissful of the Abyss.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small druid.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Welcome to Cove,\u0001the hidden city of wisdom.", 
        "keyword_1": "WISDOM", 
        "keyword_2": "PEACE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Herein is found much wisdom and peace.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Find peace in our Shrine.", 
        "name": "Frontis", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou well?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Visit our healers, I am sure they can help thee!", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Very good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an old hermit.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a recluse.", 
        "keyword_1": "RECLUSE", 
        "keyword_2": "STONE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I have withdrawn from society.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Only the ghost of Isaac who haunts the inn at Skara Brae can tell thee.", 
        "name": "Sloven", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou seen him?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Stay at the inn until he shows himself!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Ask him!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall wizard.", 
        "health": "Well, indeed.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I study the magical arts.", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGICAL ARTS", 
        "keyword_2": "GATE SPELL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "There is Truth in magic!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Since thou dost bear the Ankh I shall tell thee. A Gate spell requires Ash, Pearl, and Mandrake Root!", 
        "name": "Mentorian", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou disagree?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Good.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Well then, begone!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a shining Ankh!", 
        "health": "Bright.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I resonate with thoughts.", 
        "keyword_1": "CODEX", 
        "keyword_2": "CHAMBER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "To enter the Codex Chamber.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "One must be 8 parts Avatar have the Key of 3 Parts, the Word of Passage and know the pure Axiom!", 
        "name": "The Ankh", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Dost thou seek help?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "What are thy thoughts?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a strangely familiar bard.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I play of Love.", 
        "keyword_1": "LOVE", 
        "keyword_2": "PROBLEMS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I light a candle to our Love, in Love our problems disappear.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "But all in all we soon discover that one and one is all we long to hear!", 
        "name": "Paul", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wilt thou listen?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "About Love.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a singer.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I sing of the children.", 
        "keyword_1": "CHILDREN", 
        "keyword_2": "WORLD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "All round the world, little children being born to the world.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Got to give them all we can 'til the quest is won, then will the work be done!", 
        "name": "Linda", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Wilt thou help?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Hmm.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Teach them songs of joy!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a mystical wizard.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I use magic.", 
        "keyword_1": "BLACK STONE", 
        "keyword_2": "MOON GATE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The Black Stone is caught in a moon gate!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Stand where the gate of both moons dark shall appear. Search when the moons go dark!", 
        "name": "Merlin", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou study magic?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Best of luck with thy studies!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an old druid.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I teach the relation.", 
        "keyword_1": "RELATION", 
        "keyword_2": "", 
        "keyword_response_1": "There are eight possible combinations of Truth, Love and Courage. Each of the eight Virtues is one of those combinations!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "", 
        "name": "Draconian", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Knew ye this?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Learn the towns and castles!", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Very good!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a majestic seahorse!", 
        "health": "I am doing well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I know much of the Codex!", 
        "keyword_1": "CODEX", 
        "keyword_2": "ABYSS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The shrine Ankh knows how to enter the Chamber of the Codex!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Meditate at the Shrines of Honesty, Compassion and Valor for 3 cycles to know how to enter!", 
        "name": "Blissful", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "", 
        "question_no_answer": "", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise man.", 
        "health": "I am old but strong!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I speak of Love.", 
        "keyword_1": "LOVE", 
        "keyword_2": "HEART", 
        "keyword_response_1": "In Love, all life's contradictions dissolve and disappear.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Carry Love within it!", 
        "name": "Rabindranath Tagore", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou seek to carry Love in thy heart?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou art a fool.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thou art a good soul.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an old druid.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I sit and watch the river.", 
        "keyword_1": "RIVER", 
        "keyword_2": "WORD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "It flows endlessly.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The kings of the castles which represent the Three Principles of Virtue each know but one syllable of the Word of Passage!", 
        "name": "Brother Zair", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Agree?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Indeed.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a slender mage.", 
        "health": "Well indeed.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I know of the Codex.", 
        "keyword_1": "CODEX", 
        "keyword_2": "COMBINATION", 
        "keyword_response_1": "One must know the combination of the Three Principles of Virtue!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The combination of the Three Principles of Virtue equals the measure of time and space!", 
        "name": "Spellbind", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "", 
        "question_no_answer": "", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall mage.", 
        "health": "Quite well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I study the 'one' thing that is the secret to the Codex!", 
        "keyword_1": "STUDY", 
        "keyword_2": "CODEX", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I study of the Codex!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The one pure Axiom is more endless than the changing tides, more eternal than day and night!", 
        "name": "Shaman", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "", 
        "question_no_answer": "", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a fair sorceress.", 
        "health": "Well enough.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I ponder the key to the Axiom.", 
        "keyword_1": "KEY ", 
        "keyword_2": "AXIOM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "To the Axiom.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The 1 pure Axiom encompasses all things.", 
        "name": "Charm", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Know ye what they are?", 
        "question_no_answer": "The Truths of the universe, the Love of the heart, and the Courage of the soul!", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise mage.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I teach of the Axiom!", 
        "keyword_1": "AXIOM", 
        "keyword_2": "PARTS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The whole of the Axiom is greater than all its parts!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The measure of unending Love, the limitless Courage needed to face all obstacles, the Truth which encompasses all things!", 
        "name": "Circe", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "", 
        "question_no_answer": "", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }
]
